5/16/2021 IBRAHIM'S CV

IBRAHIM OSUMAN

PROFILE SUMMARY	CONTACT INFORMATION SOCIAL		. MEDIA
A diligent and curious professional with multi-disciplinany experience spanning geoscience, education and Information technology. My passion is learning contagious as I always strive to find expedient ways to solve complex problems. With an approachable persona, I am find it easy working with others.	Mobile number: 0241095993 Email: ibrahim.osuman@amalitech.org	<u>linkedin</u>	<u>facebook</u>

EDUCATION

Name of Institution	Location	Certificate	Completion Date
Kwame Nkrumah University of Science And Technology (KNUST)	Takoradi-Ghana	Mphil Geophysics	Nov 2017
University of Ghana (UG)	Accra-Ghana	BSc Geology	Nov 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PERIOD	NAME OF ORGANISATION OR PROJECT	POSITION	RESPOSIBILITIES	LOCATION	REFERENCE
JUNE 2018 - FEB 2021	KETEKRACHI TIMBER RECOVERY	PLANNING OFFICER/HYDROGRAPHIC SURVEYOR	Lead surveying team to search for underwater logs Analysed data using plans, maps and charts prepared survey drawings Presented data to management and wrote reports advised about technical matters on harvest planning managed overall harvesting plans Updated and analysed harvest and log yard tracking sheets	Akosombo- Ghana	ALI MARNAH- +233249542811
SEP 2017 - AUG 2019	LEAD FOR GHANA	FELLOW	Lead students to undertake project based learning related modules Prepared lesson plans Embarked on home visits to engage parents and other stakeholders in students' communities Prepared and presented progress reports, trackers etc. to management	Tamale- Ghana	Pierlina Ladzekpo - +233555766065
SEP 2016 - JULY 2017	BOSUMTWI PROJECT	Field Geophysicist	Collected Seismic, Magnetic, Electrical and Electromagnetic data. Processed Resistivity, Magnetics and IP geophysical data.	Bosumtwi- Ghana	DR. A. A. ANING - +233243670941
OCT 2016- FEB 2017	YOUTH EMPLOYMENT AGENCY	Environmental Officer	Lead the Asokore Mampong District team of environmental officers Collected and collated data on manufacturing companies in the district Inspected operations of companies/firms to ensure compliance of environmental regulations Submitted monthly reports to the regional Environmental Protection Agency office	Kumasi- Ghana	MR ARNOLD QUANSAH- +233546481471
JUN 2011 - JUNE 2012	CHIRANO GOLD MINES(KINROSS)	INTERN EXPLORATION GEOLOGIST	Lead a geochemical sampling group across the Bibiani shear zone Logged soil samples Collected and plotted soil sample data on geochemical maps and software Performed Geotechnical logging of diamond drill cores Assisted in Geological logging of diamond drill cores	Bibiani - Ghana	Mr. FELIX DONG- +233244340493/+233246211452

LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

PERIOD	ASSOCIATION	POSITION	LOCATION
JULY 2015 - MAY 2016	GRADUATE STUDENTS ASSOCIATION PARLIAMENT	SENATOR	KNUST - Ghana
JULY 2015 - MAY 2016	SOCIETY OF EXPLORATION GEOPHYSICIST (SEG)	VICE PRESIDENT	KNUST - GHANA
FEB 2010 - AUG 2010	WELFARE COMMITEE(UNIVERSITY OF GHANA SRC)	MEMBER	UG - GHANA

SKILLS

COMPUTER	FIELD WORK	SOFT SKILLS	LANGUAGES
Word Processing: Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint), Latex Python Programming (intermediate), JAVA(Beginner) Database: SQL, EXCEL GIS: ArcGIS, GEOSOFT and MAPINFO Geophysical data processing: RES2DINV AND RELEX	 Hydrographic surveying with marine acoustics and navigation systems. Designing thematic maps with ArcGIS Proficient at usage of equipment such as the Terraloc (Seismic), GSM magnetometer, GPR, Terrameter (resistivity and IP), Geologic compass, Kenometer, Petrographic microscope, and light microscope Rock, microfossil and Mineral Identification 	Time Management Supervision Decision making Problem Solving team work	Fluent in English, Akan, Wale and Hausa. Understand basic French

127.0.0.1:5500/index.html 1/1